# Subramanyam Muthyala

**(S)** 8971675036

msubramanyam901@gmail.com

Bangalore

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Cloud Network Engineer with strong skills in LAN, WAN, Routing, Switching, Cloud Computing, VNETs, Security Groups, and Firewall rules. Proficient in managing network devices including Routers, Switches, F5 Load Balancers etc. Committed to resolving network issues, enhancing security, and optimizing network performance. Collaborative team player with a proactive approach to problem-solving. Holds a bachelor's degree in computer science.

# **SKILLS / TOOLS**

Networking: LAN, WAN, Routing, Switching, VLANs, TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, BGP, OSPF, MPLS, VPN, OSI Model

Monitoring: SolarWinds, Cisco Prime, Netcool, Grafana

Ticketing/Management: ServiceNow, Microsoft ICM

Troubleshooting: Cisco Wireless controller, Wireshark, Infoblox

Scripting: PowerShell, Python

Cloud: Azure (AD, VM's, Virtual Network, NAT, DNS, Express route, Virtual WAN, VNET Peering)

**Operating System:** Windows, Linux

Database: Kusto, SQL

Excellent customer service, understanding customer needs, and building strong relationships. Ability to pay close attention to details, ensure accuracy, and maintain quality standards. Believe in accepting challenging tasks. Believe in collaboration and cooperation, hence have been a successful team player.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### SENIOR CONSULTANT, Bengaluru

LTIMindtree Ltd | Mindtree Ltd, March 2022 – Present

- Troubleshooting network connectivity issues between different data centers and regions.
- Managing network security for aggregate routers by implementing and auditing access control lists.
- Collaborating with Azure data center teams worldwide and other network teams to maintain service availability.
- Conducting regular audits on network devices to verify health and configuration.
- Leading and participating in the analysis and troubleshooting of issues with team members.
- Effective collaboration with other teams and clients to ensure project deliveries and change activities remain on track.
- Managing both network and server administration tasks.
- Leading the team and creating SOPs and TSGs for streamlined work processes.
- Creating automation workflows using PowerShell.
- Enhancing network performance through monitoring and maintenance activities
- Technologies: Network (Datacenter), Server Administration, Cloud Computing (Azure)

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ANALYST, Mumbai

Capgemini India Pvt Ltd, August 2019 - March 2022

- Managing the client's enterprise network, datacenter network, on-premises infrastructure, and cloud-based services.
- Analyzing and troubleshooting network issues.
- Managing LAN, wireless, and cloud networks.
- Serving as the primary point of contact for the team.
- Enhancing network performance through monitoring and prioritization.
- Creating and deleting DNS records.
- Assigning IP addresses.

## SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION, Bengaluru

Shankar Super Speciality Hospital, November 2018 – July 2019

- Developing web application
- Managing hospital management software
- Troubleshooting Network issues
- Software Trainer

## **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (BE) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING

Dayananda Sagar Academy of Technology and Management (DSATM), 2014 - 2018

## PRE-UNIVERSITY COLLEGE (INTERMEDIATE)

Raghavendra High-Tech PU College, 2012-14

#### SSC

RGM High School, Year 2012

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Cloud Infrastructure Services Capgemini internal Training
- AWS Cloud technical essentials Coursera
- Networking [Routing, Switching, Wireless, Firewall, Load balancer (F5)] - Cappemini internal Training
- Azure Fundamentals.

# **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

Reading Books, Bike Riding, Travelling, Listening to Music, Playing Games, Watching Movies.